DIMITRA GIANTSIDI

dimitra.giantsidi@gmail.com Informatics Forum 1.05, University of Edinburgh 10 Crichton Street, EH8 9AB, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

I like to build robust and efficient distributed systems! I am a final-year PhD student at the University of Edinburgh, UK and as part of my research, I have worked on a few interesting projects: a secure distributed transactional storage system (Trusted Execution Environments, RDMA and RocksDB), a shielded direct I/O networking for secure replication (Crash Fault Tolerant and BFT protocols) and a fast shared log for serverless computing infrastuctures (byte addressable storage, gRPC/TCP).

Currently, I am working on the design of a trusted NIC architecture for large-scale distributed systems on top of SmartNICs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ICSA, University of Edinburgh, UK

June 2023 - now

Research Assistant

- · Implementation of an RDMA-based smartNIC architecture for improved security guarantees.
- \cdot Design and optimization of robust networking protocols for fault tolerance.

Condidential Computing Group, Microsoft Research, Cambridge, UK

Sept 2021 - Dec 2021

Research Scientist Intern

· Design and implementation of a single-node KV store resilient to timing-attacks.

Cloud RnD, Intracom Telecom, Athens, Greece

Jul 2017 - Jul 2018

 $Software \ \& \ Systems \ Engineer$

 \cdot Performance and energy optimization of NFV services.

Unversity of Edinburgh, UK and TUM, Germany

Sept 2019 - present

Thesis advisor and Teaching Assistant

- · Operating Systems, Distributed Computing, Parallel Architectures, Object-oriented Programming.
- · Supervised five BSc/MSc students on their BSc Thesis on Distributed and Networking systems.

EDUCATION

University of Edinburgh, UK

Sept 2019 - present

PhD in Informatics (ICSA): Distributed systems, systems security, replication protocols

- \cdot Sponsors: Microsoft Research, UK Rise, Advisor: Pramod Bhatotia
- $\cdot \ Design \ of \ robust \ distributed \ data \ management \ systems \ leveraging \ trusted \ hardware \ and \ byte-addressable \ storage.$

University of Edinburgh, UK

Sept 2018 - Aug 2019

MSc in Computer Science: Software engineering, computer systems & high-performance computing

- · Thesis: Rollback-Resilient Transaction Protocols using Trusted Counters, Advisor: Pramod Bhatotia
- \cdot Secure transaction protocols for LSM-based KV stores.

National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Greece

Sept 2012 - Feb 2018

Diploma (5-year joint degree, BEng and MEng) in Electrical & Computer Engineering

- · Thesis: Improving QoS in modern multi-core servers with Dynamic Cache Partitioning, Advisor: Georgios Goumas
- \cdot Secure transaction protocols for LSM-based KV stores.

PUBLICATIONS

Anchor: Secure Persistent Memory Architecture, SIGMOD'24

Dimitris Stravakakis, Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Philip Saendig, Shady Issa, Pramod Bhatotia.

FlexLog: A Shared Log for Stateful Serverless Computing, ACM HPDC'23

Dimitra Giantsidi, Emmanouil Giortamis, Nathaniel Tornow, Florin Dinu, Pramod Bhatotia.

Treaty: Secure Distributed Transactions, IEEE/IFIP DSN'22 (Best paper nominee)

Dimitra Giantsidi, Maurice Bailleu, Natacha Crooks, Pramod Bhatotia.

Avocado: A Secure In-Memory Distributed Storage System, USENIX ATC'21

Maurice Bailleu, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasilis Gavrielatos, Le Quoc Do, Vijay Nagarajan, Pramod Bhatotia.

DICER: Diligent Cache Partitioning for Efficient Workload Consolidation, ICPP'21

Konstantinos Nikas, Nikela Papadopoulou, Dimitra Giantsidi, Vasileios Karakostas, Georgios I Goumas, Nectarios Koziris.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages C/C++, Python, Bash, Golang, Java

Systems Programming RocksDB and folly libraries, TEEs (Intel SGX, OpenEnclave SDK, AMD-sev),

direct network I/O (DPDK, RDMA, Alveo SmartNICs), SPDK,

Intel RDT, LLVM, collectd, POSIX/Unix, OpenMP and MPI, gRPC

Virtualization KVM, Qemu/Libvirt, Docker, Kubernetes

Version Control Git

Distributed Programming Hadoop MapReduce, Socket and RPC programming

HONORS AND AWARDS

PhD scolarship, Microsoft Research 2019

Claire Jones Prize, Adelard 2019

Prize for Best Performing Female MSc Student at the University of Edinburgh

Highest Honors award 2012

Top 0.1% in national qualification exams, GPA: 19.6/20

PROFILES

Personal site https://dgiantsidi.github.io/